Vernon Greene Papers
Vernon Greene Papers
- Works by others
  - Priscella's Pop by Al Vermeer
    - Promotional material and sketch, circa 1950s; undated; 8 items (Oversize 24)
    - Proofs (Sunday), 1952 Jun-Jul; 1953 Jul-Oct; 22 items (Oversize 24)
    - Proofs (daily), 1953; 97 items (Oversize 24)
    - Tearsheets and clippings (color Sunday), 1953 Sep-1954 Mar; also includes one black and white daily; 15 items (Oversize 24)
  - Professor Phumble by Bill Yates
    - Proofs (daily), Sep 4-9 1961; Nov 11-25 1961; 2 items (Oversize 17)
  - Pussycat Princess by Ed Anthony, Grace Dayton and Ruth Carroll
    - Tearsheets (color Sunday), 1935 Nov-1938 Jan (Oversize 13)
  - Red Ryder by Fred Harman
    - Drawings, 1965; undated (Box 13)
    - Postcards, undated (Box 13)
  - Reg'lar Fellows by Gene Byrnes
    - Proofs (color Sunday), 1935 Feb-Mar; 8 items (Oversize 18)
  - Regular Folks by Jefferson Machamer
    - Proofs, 1933; undated; 9 items; magazine advertising for Ex-Lax (Oversize 15)
  - Rex Morgan, M.D. by Dal Curtis
    - Clippings, 1949; 9 items (Oversize 24)
  - Rick Kane, Space Marshal by Walter Gibson and E.C. Stoner
    - Proofs, 1951 (Oversize 19)
  - Right Around Home by Dudley Fisher
    - Proofs (Sunday), May 1 1938 (Oversize 19)
  - Rivets by George Sixta
    - Proofs (daily), 1953 Mar-1956 Nov; includes 3 color proofs; 179 items (Oversize 10)
    - Proofs (daily), 1953-1956; 2 folders (Oversize 29)
  - Rosie's Beau by George McManus
    - Proofs, Feb 2 1938 (Oversize 13)
    - Clippings (color Sunday), 1933-1938; 1939 Jan-Apr,; 1939 Jul-Nov,; 1940 Jan-Jul,; 1940 Sep-1942 May,; 1942 Sep,; Sep 12 1943,; Mar 12 1944; 2 folders (Oversize 13)
  - Roy Rodgers by Al McKimson
    - Proofs (daily and Sunday), 1950-1951; 73 sheets (Oversize 15)
  - Rusty Riley by Frank Godwin
    - Proofs, 1951 May-Nov (Oversize 10)
  - S'atter Pop by Charles Payne
    - Proofs, undated (Box 13)
  - Secret Agent X9
    - Proofs (daily) by Robert Storm, 1939 Jun; 1940 Jan-Jun; 26 sheets (Oversize 21)
    - Proofs for El Agente Secreto X-9 by Dashiell Hammett, Oct 7-12 1935; Oct 21-26 1935; 2 sheets (Oversize 21)
  - Sentinel Louie
    - Clippings, 1936-1937; 11 items (Oversize 20)
  - Sister Susie by Alice Harvey
    - Tearsheets (color Sunday), 1936; 18 items (Oversize 13)
  - Newspaper Enterprise Association
    - "Six Days with NEA" Promotional book, 1952 (Oversize 30)
  - Skippy by Percy Crosby
    - Clippings (color Sunday), May 4 1929; May 28 1933,; Jun 23 1935,; 1936,; 1937 Jan,; 1937 Jun-Jul; 1929 strip is in black and white (Oversize 20)
    - Proofs (daily), 1937; 21 sheets (Oversize 21)
  - Smilin' Jack by Jack Mosley
    - Proofs (color Sunday), Feb 7 1954; 1 item (Box 13)
  - Smitty by Walter Berndt
    - Proofs (color Sunday), Feb 28 1954 (Box 13)
    - Tearsheets (color Sunday), 1934-1938 (Oversize 14)
  - Smokey Stover by Bill Holman
    - Clippings, 1936-1938 (Oversize 14)
      1936: May 3, 31, Jun 7, 21, 28, Jul 26, Aug 2, 9, 16, Oct 25,
      1937: Apr 25, May 16, Jun 6, Jul 25, Aug 22, Sep 12, Oct 10, 31, Dec 5, 26
      1938: Jan 9, Feb 6
    - Proofs (color Sunday), 1956; 1958-1959; on same sheet as other cartoons- often Rick O'Shay, Teenie Weenies, Sweeney and Son; 102 items (Oversize 23)
    - Proofs (color Sunday), Jan 24 1954; Jan 31 1954 (Box 13)
  - Snookums by George McManus
    - Proofs (Sunday), Sep 1 1946; Jun 22 1947,; Nov 2 1947,; Dec 18 1949,; Feb 21 1954,; Apr 18 1954,; May 23 1954,; Oct 24 1954,; Nov 7 1954,; Dec 12 1954; 10 items (Oversize 10)
    - Proofs (Sunday), 1946-1954 (Box 13)
    - Clippings (color Sunday), Sep 9 1951; 1951; 2 items (Box 24)
  - Steve Canyon by Milt Caniff
    - Proofs for promotional material, undated (Box 13)
  - Sunday Mirror Comic Section
    - Clippings (color), Aug 1937; 1938 Feb-May (Oversize 14)
  - Sunflower Street by Tom Little
    - Proofs (daily), Aug 23-Sep 4 1937; 2 sheets (Oversize 19)
      See the
      C.D. Russell Cartoons
      .
  - Sweeney and Son, Jinglet, Them Days Are Gone Forever by Al Posen
    - Scrapbooks, 1933 Oct-1935 Aug; 1945 Jan-1946 Dec; color Sunday clippings and proofs; 2 items (Oversize 31)
  - Take it Easy Pop by Charles Payne
    - Artwork and proofs, undated (Oversize 24)
    - Scrapbook, undated (Oversize 24)
  - Ted Towers Animal Master by Joe King and Frank Buck
    - Proofs (Sunday), 1935 Jun-Jul; 1935 Sep,; 1935 Nov-1936 May (Oversize 15)
    - Tearsheets (color Sunday), 1935 Sep; 1935 Nov-Dec,; 1936-1937,; 1938 Jan (Oversize 17)
  - Teena by Hilda Terry
    - Clippings (color Sunday), 1957; 11 items (Oversize 14)
      Jan 13, Mar 3, 17, 24, 31, Apr 14, 28, Jun 9, Sep 8, 22, Oct 13
  - Teenie Weenies by William Donahey
    - Proofs (color Sunday), Jan 24 1954; Jan 31 1954; 2 items (Box 13)
  - Terry and the Pirates by Milton Caniff
    - Comic books, circa 1936; circa 1938; Large Feature Comic No. 27 and unnumbered; 2 items (Box 32)
    - Engraving mats, 1961; 2 items (Box 13)
    - Proofs, 1936; Aug 28-Sep 7 1961; 3 sheets (Oversize 21)
    - Tearsheets (color Sunday), 1935-1941; 160 items (Oversize 17)
  - That's My Pop and Count Screwloose by Milt Gross
    - Tearsheets (color Sunday), 1935-1937; 17 items (Oversize 14)
      1935- Feb 10, 17; Mar 7, Oct 6, Nov 24, Dec 5, 29
      1936- Mar 29, Apr 5; May 31, Jun 28, Jul 14
      1937- Jan 3, 10, 30, May 23, Oct 10
  - Tillie the Toiler by Russ Westover
    - Clippings (color Sunday), 1933-1937 (Oversize 26)
    - Proofs (Sunday), 1936-1937 (Oversize 26)
  - Timid Soul by H.T. Webster
    - Clippings (color Sunday), 1935 Oct-Nov; 1936 Mar-Apr,; 1936 Jun-Aug; 8 items (Oversize 20)
    - Clippings (color Sunday), Aug 28 1949; Sep 11 1949,; Sep 25 1949; 3 items (Oversize 14)
  - Tiny Tim by Stanley Link
    - Clippings (color Sunday), 1936-1938; 8 items (Oversize 14)
    - Proofs (color Sunday), Jan 24 1954; Feb 14 1954,; Feb 21 1954; 3 items (Box 13)
  - Tippie by Edwina
    - Tearsheets, May 18 1935; Sep 14 1935,; 1935 Nov-1938 Jan; 99 items (Oversize 17)
  - Toodles by the Baers
    - Proofs and Tearsheets (daily), 1947 (Oversize 29)
  - Toonerville Folks by Fontaine Fox
    - Clippings (color Sunday), 1935-1938; 16 items (Oversize 14)
      1935- Dec 29
      1936- Jun 28; Jul 12, 26, Aug 2, 9, 16, Sep 13, Oct 4
      1937- Jan 3, May 23, Aug 15, Nov 7, Dec 12
      1938- Jan 2, Feb 20
  - Torchy Togs by Jackie Ormes
    - Proofs, 1951; 2 items; paper doll cut outs; also includes a sheet of Torchy in Heartbeats (Box 13)
  - U.S. Savings Bonds
    - Proof, 1949 (Oversize 29)
  - Wall Street Wife by G.R.S., Russell Patterson, Everett Shimm
    - Proofs, circa 1920s-1930s; serialized story; 17 items (Oversize 19)
  - Young Woman by Carmen Barnes and R. Van Buren
    - Proofs, 1935; serialized story; 19 items (Oversize 19)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Cartoons, illustrations and artwork
      - Comic strip clippings and proofs, undated; includes Porky and Daffy (Oversize 33)
      - Newspaper Enterprise Association Award Nominee proofs, undated; different category contained on each sheet (Oversize 24)
      - Original artwork (Box 13)
        Bruce Hyslop "Congratulations, It's a Boy
        Michael Della Penta
        Michael Berry
        Tracing of Jimmy Hatlo "Little Iodine" by a 6 year old
        Irwin Hasen
        Ben Roth "Girls"
        R.A. Lewis "The Way to a man's heart"
        Tony Scarfino "Snuffy Smith"
        Jim Malone "Mox Nix"
        Jay "Ding" Darling watercolor inscribed to Al Posen
        "Joy and Gloom" General foods ltd, Coburg, Ontario
        "Roving Cartoonist Wrapped Up in his work! drawing by L.D. Warren
      - Proof by Joe King, undated; 1 item (Oversize 24)
      - Sketches and proof sheet by Russell Patterson, undated; 1933 Nov,; circa 1940s (Box 13, Oversize 24)
      - Miscellaneous Proofs, undated (Box 13)
      - Proofs of paintings by William A. Smith, undated (Oversize 23)
    - Sound recordings
      - #51 "The Art of Laughter" by John Mason Brown, undated (Box 45)
      - #52 H.R. 7927 Statement by John K. Herbert, circa ???? (Oversize 33)
      - #53 Memorial service for Greene, eulogy by Rube Goldberg, Riverside Church, circa 1965 (Oversize 33)
      - #54 "Missing Links" by Ira Skutch with Greene, 1963; includes two pieces of correspondence (Box 15)
    - Writings
      - Address by Myra Bennett, May 29 1962; topic is journalism education; mimeographed copy; 14 pages (Box 13)
      - Short story "Friends of the Family" by S.M. Smith, circa 1936; mimeographed copy; 14 pages (Box 13)
      - Statement on H.R. 7927 by John K. Herbert, 1962; 31 pages (Box 13)
      - Synopsis of comic strip "Hollie Wood" by William A. Smith, undated (Box 13)
      - Synopsis of "Santa Claus & Company" by Max Trell, circa 1937; includes letter from King Features to Paul Fung (Box 13)
      - True Romance story "Leap Year Bride!" by Miriam Hecht, 1951; 1 page (Box 15)
      - Miscellaneous writings by unidentified authors (Box 15)
        A Story of Comic and Adventure Stripes and Pages and the National Background of Some of America's Leading Artists; Saturday Adventure Audition II; Stuyvesant Town; (Train Gags); History of Comics Section III- The Popularity of Comics; Polly and her Pals Daily; Ted Towers; untitled miscellaneous